Guide to the John Chipman Farrar Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
John Chipman Farrar papers
1916-1974
YCAL MSS 437
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
16.48
(42 boxes)
The John Chipman Farrar Papers consist of correspondence, subject files, manuscripts, personal papers, and printed material relating to the personal and professional life of John Chipman Farrar, and to a lesser degree, his wife Margaret Petherbridge Farrar, between 1916 and 1974. The Papers also document the publishing firms Farrar and Rinehart and Farrar, Straus, and Giroux. A number of authors' correspondence and drafts are included in the Papers.
Farrar, John Chipman, 1896-1974
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift, John Chipman Farrar, 1964-1967 (Yale 1919) and Margaret Petherbridge Farrar, 1976.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Associated Materials
Scrapbook, Yale 1918 and the War, compiled by Hamilton Hadley and John C. Farrar, of the Class of 1918, Yale College (Yez 918had+ Oversize). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University.
Various sound recordings. Yale Collection of Historical Sound Recordings, Yale University. Please see details in Appendix A.
John Chipman Farrar (1896-1974)
The publisher John Chipman Farrar was born to Edward Donaldson Farrar and Sally Wright in Burlington, Vermont, in 1896. Farrar attended Yale between 1914 and 1919. His education at Yale was interrupted with a year of service with the Intelligence Division of the Army Air Service during World War I.
Early in his life Farrar aspired to be an author, and during his time at Yale he published two volumes of verse ( Portraits and Forgotten Shrines ), wrote and produced a play, Nerves, worked on the Yale Literary Magazine and co-edited the Yale Book of Student Verse, 1910-1919. While at Yale University Farrar met Stephen Vincent Benet, with whom he collaborated on several publications and projects.
After graduation Farrar went on to work as a reporter and to publish poetry; however, he is best known as a publisher and editor. Farrar's first publishing job was with George Doran in 1921; when the firm merged and became Doubleday, Doran & Company in 1927, Farrar was promoted within the company. In 1927 Farrar and his colleague Stanley Rinehart formed a publishing company together. While successful for a number of years, the men separated in 1946, at which time Farrar created Farrar, Straus & Company with Roger Straus. Farrar and Straus would remain in partnership throughout the rest of their lives, with the company adopting several names over its lifetime, including Farrar, Straus & Young, Farrar, Straus & Cudahy, and Farrar, Straus, & Giroux.
In addition to maintaining his publishing firm, Farrar was also involved in encouraging authors. In 1926 he founded the Breadloaf Writers' Conference at Middlebury College with Robert Frost. He served as the president of the New York Chapter of the International Association of Poets, Playwrights, Editors, Essayists, and Novelists (PEN), as director of the Marlboro Fiction Writers' Conference (1949-1951), and on the boards of the Poetry Society of America and the Writers' Board for World Government. Farrar also taught at New York University (early 1920s) and Columbia University (1945-1947).
In 1926 John Farrar and Margaret Petherbridge Farrar (1897-1984) married. A graduate of Smith College (1919), Margaret Farrar is best known for her work editing crossword puzzles for Simon & Schuster and The New York Times. She also played a role in publishing; she was editor of mystery books at Farrar & Rinehart and Farrar, Straus, & Giroux and served as a member of the board of directors of Farrar, Straus, & Giroux following John Farrar's death in 1974. John and Margaret Petherbridge Farrar had three children: John Curtis Farrar, Alison Farrar Wilson, and Janice Farrar Thaddeus.
Scope and Contents
The Papers consist of correspondence, subject files, manuscripts, personal papers, and printed material relating to the personal and professional life of John C. Farrar, and to a lesser degree, Margaret Petherbridge Farrar. In addition the Papers document the work of the publishing firms Farrar & Rinehart and Farrar, Straus, and Giroux.
The Papers concern Farrar's publishing career through his correspondence with G. H. Doran and with his partners in Farrar & Rinehart and Farrar, Straus, and Giroux. The correspondence and subject files also contain Farrar's correspondence with authors, which often include drafts of writings. Among the authors represented in the correspondence are: Hervey Allen, Stephen Vincent Benét, Katherine Brush, James Branch Cabell, Hoagie Carmichael, Floyd Dell, T.S. Eliot, James Galvin, Amy Lowell, Roi Ottley, Alec Waugh, and Thornton Wilder. Art and objects in the Papers also provide insight into Farrar's relationship with authors; for example, following Amy Lowell's death Farrar was given one of her boxes of cigars.
The Papers also represent Farrar's writing career, including drafts of poetry, essays, and plays, in addition to correspondence with potential collaborators and publishers.
Farrar's engagement with writing and publishing is further illustrated through his correspondence relating to his work to establish the Breadloaf Writers' Conference and to revive the New York Chapter of the International Association of Poets, Playwrights, Editors, Essayists, and Novelists (PEN), as well as to teaching stints at New York University and Columbia University. Farrar was also involved in a number of civic and religious organizations as the correspondence and subject files evidence.
Documents regarding Farrar's relationship with his mother Sally Wright, wife Margaret Farrar, and their children John Curtis, Alison, and Janice, can be found in the Family Papers. Correspondence to Margaret Farrar can also be found in the general correspondence and subject files.
Arrangement
Organized into four series: I. Correspondence and Subject Files, 1917-1974. II. Writings, 1919-1967. III. Family Papers, 1934-1964. IV. Printed Material, 1916-1964.
Appendix A: Sound Recordings
The following list provides details about sound recordings from the John Chipman Farrar Papers located at the Yale Collection of Historical Sound Recordings.
YT7-3968 Nightmare at noon by Steven Vincent Benét, noon, Henry Hull, reader, nd, WOR Mightier than the sword: John Farrar, host; Max Lerner, guest, June 3, 1943: The mind and faith of Justice Holmes
YT7-3969 Mightier than the sword: John Farrar, host, June 17, 1943: Adelaide Hawley, guest Mightier than the sword, John Farrar, host, July 8, 1943: Maurice Hinduce [possibly Maurice G. Hindus]
YT7-3970 Mightier than the sword: John Farrar, host, July 15, 1943: Josephine Von Miklos, guest
YT7-3974 Day of reckoning, John Farrar, announcer, April 3, 1943: [program about Quisling]
YT7-3975 They burned the books [series title ?], John Farrar, announcer, May 5, 1943, written by Steven Vincent Benét
YT7-3976 Day of reckoning, John Farrar, announcer, April 10, 1943 [incomplete, Parts 3 & 5 only]
YT7-3977 They burned the books, John Farrar, announcer, May 11, 1943, written by Steven Vincent Benét [incomplete: 5 of 6 sides, but Side 4 unplayable]
YT7-3978 Dear Adolf, John Farrar, announcer, June 21, 1942, first of [a series of] six, Steven Vincent Benét, writer [same] No. 3 of 6, July 5, 1942
YT7-3979 Dear Adolf, John Farrar, announcer, July 12, 1942, no. 4 of 6, Steven Vincent Benét, writer: Part 5 [only] [same program] John Farrar, announcer, August 2, 1942, No. 6 of 6, Steven Vincent Benét, writer Tribute to Steven Vincent Benét, April 15, 1943 [incomplete: 2 of 6 sides only; 1 disc missing, 1 damaged and unplayable]
Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Publishers and publishing; Writers' retreats -- United States; Allen, Hervey, 1889-1949; Benét, S. V. (Stephen Vincent), 1827-1895; Cabell, James Branch, 1879-1958; Farrar, John Chipman, 1896-1974; Farrar, Margaret Petherbridge; Lowell, Amy, 1874-1925; Ottley, Roi, 1906-1960; Waugh, Alec, 1898-1981; Wilder, Thornton, 1897-1975; Willkie, Wendell L. (Wendell Lewis), 1892-1944; Brandt & Brandt; Century Club (New York, N.Y.); Doubleday, Doran & Company; Farrar, Straus, and Giroux; Farrar & Rinehart; PEN (Organization); United World Federalists (U.S.)
- Correspondence and Subject Files, 1917-1974; Series I; 13.35; (32 boxes)
  Arrangement
  The series is organized into two subseries: General Correspondence and Subject Files and Publishing Correspondence and Subject Files. Each subseries is arranged alphabetically by correspondent or subject. Unsorted correspondence is filed at the end of the General Correspondence subseries.
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains correspondence and subject files dating from 1917 to 1974 that document the personal and professional life of John Chipman Farrar, and, to a lesser degree, Margaret Farrar. The General Correspondence and Subject Files subseries contains documents relating to Farrar's relationship with publishing firms and authors as well as involvement in various organizations. The Publishing Correspondence and Subject Files subseries pertains to the publishing firms Farrar & Rinehart and Farrar, Straus, and Giroux.
  - General Correspondence and Subject Files
    - "A" General, circa 1934-1967; 5 (Box 1)
    - Allen, Hervey, 1944-1953; 3 (Box 2)
      Includes "The Passing of Amy Lowell," typescript.
    - Alpha Delta Phi, 1963-1964 (Box 2)
    - Alston, Mary Niven, 1963 (Box 2)
    - Anglican Fiction Award, 1959-1964 (Box 2)
    - Anglican Prize Novel Contest, 1958-1962; 2 (Box 2)
    - American Legion, 1942-1943 (Box 2)
    - Applications to Farrar, Straus, and Giroux, 1966 (Box 2)
    - Armistead, George C., Jr. M.D., 1954-1966; 2 (Box 2)
    - Asia, Committee for Free, 1953-1954 (Box 2)
    - Asia Foundation, 1960; 3 (Box 3)
    - Astroflash horoscope for John Farrar, 1970 (Box 3)
    - Authors, 1940 (Box 3)
      Includes letters requesting permission to perform plays written by Farrar and letters from Archie Coates, Edith Drake, and others.
    - "B" General, circa 1934-1968; 10 (Box 3–4)
      Includes correspondence with John Hans Bamberger, Sgt. William Baker, Eleanor Robson Belmont, Kingman Brewster, Ulric Bell, W.V. Bowman and regarding the Breadloaf Writers' Conference.
    - Baldwin, Faith, 1934-1939, undated (Box 4)
    - Bates, Katharine Lee, 1924-1929 (Box 4)
    - Baverstock, Sylvia, 1945-1946 (Box 4)
    - Beechwood Players Club, 1941-1942 (Box 4)
    - Beer, Thomas, undated (Box 4)
    - Behrman, Sam N., 1973 (Box 4)
    - Belmont, Eleanor Robson, 1955-1965; 2 (Box 5)
    - Benét, Laura, 1943 (Box 5)
    - Benét Memorial Program, 1943; 2 (Box 5)
    - Benét, Stephen Vincent, circa 1940; 2 (Box 5)
    - Benét, William Rose, 1917-1935 (Box 5)
    - Berdan (Professor) Dinner, 1938 (Box 5)
    - Beston, Henry, 1928-1929 (Box 5)
    - Birkbeck, Barbara Ann, 1960-1967 (Box 5)
    - Blake, Christopher, 1959-1962; 2 (Box 5)
    - B'nai Brith Great Book Series General Correspondence, 1959-1960; 2 (Box 6)
    - Book Fair, 1936; 2 (Box 6)
      Contains correspondence from several authors regarding the New York Times Book Fair.
    - Boyd, James, 1928 (Box 6)
    - Bradford, Gamaliel, 1923-1929 (Box 6)
    - Brandt & Brandt, 1926-1971 (Box 6)
    - Bromfield, Louise, 1926-1935 (Box 6)
    - Bronson, F.W., 1948-1949 (Box 6)
    - Brooke, Margaret, Lady, undated (Box 6)
    - Brush, Katharine, 1944 (Box 6)
    - Bryant, Kay, 1950-1956 (Box 6)
    - Butcher, Fanny, 1943-1973 (Box 6)
    - Bynner, Witter, 1935 (Box 6)
    - "C" General, circa 1934-1968; 7 (Box 6–7)
      Includes correspondence regarding the Cabell Society, Citizens for Victory, statement regarding death of Colette, and correspondence from Norton Conway, John O'Hara Cosgrove, Carolyn Coffin, Celso Al. Carunungan, Hugh Chisholm, and Brewster Crawford.
    - Cabell, James Branch, 1946-1947 (Box 7)
    - Carmichael, Hoagy, 1963-1964 (Box 7)
    - Carncross, Ruth E. "Amy Lowell... A Bibliography," typescript, 1926 (Box 7)
    - Century Club, 1956-1969; 5 (Box 8)
    - Christmas Cards Acknowledged, 1966 (Box 8)
    - Council for Democracy, 1941 (Box 8)
    - "D" General, circa 1934-1968; 4 (Box 8)
      Includes correspondence from Barnard DeVoto, George H. Doran, Dodd, Mead & Company, Mary Doran Rinehart (includes snapshot of Farrar), John Dos Passos, Owen Dodson, George Dickerson, and Dr. P.M. Dawley.
    - Dell, Floyd, 1941-1970 (Box 9)
    - Des Jardins, Katherine, 1966-1967 (Box 9)
    - Doran, George H., 1946-1951 (Box 9)
    - Dreiser, 1958-1959 (Box 9)
      Contains correspondence from Kyra Markham regarding publication of her letters with Theodore Dreiser.
    - Dutch Treat Club, 1963-1967 (Box 9)
    - "E" General, circa 1934-1968; 3 (Box 9)
      Includes correspondence from Lucia Ewing and Ralph Ellison, Max Eastman, Richenda Ellis, and Walter Prichard Eaton.
    - Editors Lunch Club, 1956-1959 (Box 9)
    - Eliot, T.S., 1956-1963 (Box 9)
    - Episcopal Matters, 1960-1961 (Box 9)
    - "F" General, circa 1934-1968; 4 (Box 9)
      Includes correspondence between John Farrar and family members and well as correspondence with Edna Ferber and Malcolm Foster.
    - Fairfield Foundation, 1958-1964 (Box 10)
    - Farrar, Margaret, 1950 (Box 10)
    - Ficke Sonnets, 1963 (Box 10)
      Contains material relating to the Arthur Davison Ficke Memorial Award including "John Farrar's list for Ficke award" and copies of sonnets.
    - Ficke Poetry Awards, 1964 (Box 10)
    - Foundations, 1959 (Box 10)
    - Fuller, Edmund, 1949-1951 (Box 10)
    - Frost, Robert, 1935 (Box 10)
    - "G" General, circa 1934-1968; 5 (Box 10)
      Includes correspondence from Zane Grey, Willa Gibbs, and Guggenheim Foundation.
    - Galante, Kenneth R., 1964 (Box 11)
    - Galvin, James, 1963-1965 (Box 11)
    - Glueck, Nelson, 1962-1964 (Box 11)
    - Goode, Gerald, 1964-1965 (Box 11)
    - Green, Edward M., 1964-1965 (Box 11)
    - Group: Church Writing Group, 1959 (Box 11)
    - "H" General, circa 1934-1968; 5 (Box 11–12)
      Includes correspondence from Alexander Hertz, Ted Hughes, Hamilton Hadley, Dorothy Halifax, and Huddee Herrick.
    - Hauser, Gayelord, 1961-1962 (Box 12)
    - Herrick, Huddee, 1959-1963 (Box 12)
    - Herrick, Robert, 1960 (Box 12)
    - Hertz, Alexander, 1961-1962 (Box 12)
    - Heyward, Dorothy, 1935 (Box 12)
    - Holy Cross Press, 1959-1961 (Box 12)
    - Howard, Sidney, 1936, undated (Box 12)
    - Hunter, Edward, 1957-1959; 2 (Box 12)
    - "I" General, circa 1934-1968; 2 (Box 12)
    - "J" General, circa 1934-1968; 3 (Box 12)
      Includes correspondence from C.D. Jackson and Grace Jackson.
    - Janes, R. Paul, Jr. "A Song for Christmas", undated (Box 12)
    - "K" General, circa 1934-1968; 4 (Box 13)
      Includes correspondence from Frances Parkson Keyes and Messmore Kendall.
    - Kendall (Messmore) Campaign, 1940 (Box 13)
    - Kennedy, John F. Campaign, 1960 (Box 13)
    - "L" General, circa 1934-1968; 4 (Box 13)
      Includes correspondence from Henry Luce, Amy Loveman, and booklet of poetry called "Brush Strokes" by W.L. Little.
    - Lee, Chin, 1962 (Box 14)
    - Lehman, Milton. "Goddard Story", 1960-1965; 2 (Box 14)
    - Leibowitz, Sam. "Projected Book", 1962 (Box 14)
    - Lelen, J. M., Rev., 1958 (Box 14)
    - Library of St. Bede, 1960-1964 (Box 14)
    - Lincoln School, 1939-1941; 3 (Box 14)
    - Lists, 1954-1960, undated (Box 14)
      Various lists of names and addresses.
    - Longstreet, Stephen. See also: Carmichael, Hoagy, undated (Box 14)
    - Lowell, Amy, 1921-1925 (Box 14)
    - "M" General, circa 1934-1968; 7 (Box 14–15)
      Includes correspondence from Archibald MacLeish, Edna St. Vincent Millay, H.L. Mencken, and Edmond McKenna.
    - Macaulay, Robie, 1959-1966 (Box 15)
    - McKenna, Edmond, 1962-1963 (Box 15)
    - MacPhail, Norman C., 1947-1950 (Box 15)
    - Marlboro Fiction Writer's Conference, 1950-1951; 3 (Box 16)
    - Maugham, W. Somerset (William Somerset), 1965-1967 (Box 16)
      Contains correspondence about The Making of a Saint by Maugham (but not correspondence with Maugham).
    - Meerloo, Joost A. M., 1957 (Box 16)
    - Meisel, Fred, 1954 (Box 16)
    - Moffett, Cleveland. "An Equivocal Welcome", 1959-1960 (Box 16)
    - Morhaim, Victoria, 1960 (Box 16)
    - Mowrer, Lillian, 1960 (Box 16)
    - Mundell, William, 1955-1957; 3 (Box 16)
    - "N" General, circa 1934-1968; 3 (Box 16)
      Includes correspondence from Charles G. ("Ceegee") Norris (with photographs), New York Times, Noble and Noble, Benjamin Nangle, and Ed Naughton.
    - National Conference of Christians and Jews, 1950-1971 (Box 16)
    - National Arts Club, 1960 (Box 17)
    - Noonday Press, 1960 (Box 17)
    - Norris, Charles G. (Ceegee), undated (Box 17)
      Includes photograph.
    - "O" General, circa 1934-1968; 4 (Box 17)
      Includes correspondence from H.G. Owen and Eugene O'Neill.
    - Ottley, Roi. "The White Marble Lady", 1964; 2 (Box 17)
    - "P" General, circa 1934-1968; 6 (Box 17–18)
      Includes correspondence from Frank J. Palescandolo, Jim Phelan, Joseph Phelan, Katherine Paton, and Poetry Society of America.
    - Page, Elizabeth, 1946-1964; 2 (Box 18)
    - Parkhurst, Helen. "A Boy Called Tony", 1962-1964 (Box 18)
    - Parsons, James B. (Judge). Untitled autobiography, 1961-1964 (Box 18)
    - Party Lists, 1948-1951 (Box 18)
    - Pathway Books, 1957 (Box 18)
    - Pauker, John, 1946 (Box 18)
    - PEN (Organization)
      - General Correspondence, 1951-1965; 18 (Box 18–20)
      - "Important", 1964-1967 (Box 20)
      - "Japan", 1957-1958 (Box 21)
      - "Paris", 1958-1959 (Box 21)
      - "Poland", 1958 (Box 21)
      - "Translation Committee", 1959-1960 (Box 21)
      - "Trip to Far East", 1961-1962 (Box 21)
    - Poetry Society of America, 1958-1965 (Box 21)
    - Prize contests, 1959 (Box 21)
      Correspondence regarding the Lamont Poetry Selection contest.
    - Project folder & projected books, 1962 (Box 21)
      Contains letter to David Susskind
    - Publishers' Lunch Club, 1949-1964; 2 (Box 21)
    - "Q" General, circa 1934-1968; 3 (Box 21)
    - "R" General, circa 1934-1968; 4 (Box 22)
      Includes correspondence from Stanley Rinehart, Elizabeth Ross, and Mann Rubin.
    - Reik, Theodore, 1950-1964; 4 (Box 22)
    - Religious drama, 1956-1962 (Box 22)
    - Religious list, 1963-1966 (Box 22)
    - Rinehart, 1944-1949 (Box 22)
    - Rochester Poetry Contest, 1963-1965 (Box 22)
    - Ross, Sam. "The Outcast", 1964 (Box 22)
    - Royer, Fanchon, 1957-1964 (Box 22)
    - "S" General, circa 1934-1968; 6 (Box 23)
      Includes correspondence from Carl Sandburg, Bernard Sobel, and Chard Powers Smith.
    - Scarborough Presbyterian Church, 1943 (Box 24)
    - Scarborough School
      - Board of Directors, 1941-1943; 9 (Box 24–25)
      - Spanish-American folder, 1941 (Box 25)
    - Schnabel, Arthur, 1957 (Box 25)
    - Smith, William Gardner. "The Stone Face", 1962 (Box 25)
    - Special Committees, 1964 (Box 25)
      Contains pamphlet for International Study and Research Institute.
    - Sullivan, Frank, 1944 (Box 25)
    - Sullivan, Margaret. "Maggie" by Kenneth Wagg, 1963-1964 (Box 25)
    - Swinnerton, Frank, 1925-1928, 1965 (Box 25)
    - "T" General, circa 1934-1968; 4 (Box 26)
    - Taft, Charles P., 1936 (Box 26)
    - Tiedeman, Karl, 1961-1966 (Box 26)
    - Town Hall Club, 1940 (Box 26)
    - Truman, Harry, 1952 (Box 26)
    - "U" General, circa 1934-1968; 4 (Box 26)
    - Unesco, 1958 (Box 26)
    - Union Theological Seminary, 1959-1962 (Box 26)
    - United States. Office of War Information, 1943; 2 (Box 26)
    - United World Federalists, 1949-1952; 4 (Box 27)
    - "V" General, circa 1934-1968; 2 (Box 27)
    - Vorys, John, 1962 (Box 27)
    - Vorys, Martin, 1961 (Box 27)
    - "W" General, circa 1934-1968; 5 (Box 27–28)
      Includes correspondence from Thornton Wilder.
    - Waugh, Alec, 1946, 1966-1968 (Box 28)
    - Wayman, Dorothy, 1958-1960; 3 (Box 28)
    - Westchester Council, 1941 (Box 28)
    - Weissman, Jessica, undated; 1 (Box 28)
    - West, Rebecca, 1926 (Box 28)
    - Whitridge, Arnold, 1959-1960 (Box 28)
    - Wigoder, Devorah, 1964-1965 (Box 28)
    - Wilder, Thornton, 1928, 1948 (Box 28)
    - Willkie, Wendell, 1941-1942; 2 (Box 28)
    - Wilson, Edmund, 1953 (Box 28)
    - Wodehouse, P. G., 1946 (Box 28)
    - Wright, J. S., 1945-1946 (Box 29)
    - Wylie, Edmund, 1936-1941; 3 (Box 29)
    - "X-Y-Z" General, circa 1934-1968; 4 (Box 29)
    - Yale Literary Magazine, 1958-1961; 2 (Box 29)
    - Yale University, 1942-1975 (Box 29)
    - Unsorted correspondence, circa 1931-1973; 18 (Box 30–31)
  - Publishing Correspondence and Subject Files
    - Farrar & Rinehart, 1944-1946 (Box 32)
    - Farrar, Straus, and Cudahy, 1956-1964 (Box 32)
    - Farrar, Straus, and Company, 1946-1956 (Box 32)
    - Farrar, Straus, and Giroux, 1969-1973; 2 (Box 32)
    - Miscellaneous office memos, 1959-1964; 2 (Box 32)
- Writings, 1919-1967, undated; Series II; 1.46; (4 boxes)
  Arranged alphabetically by title.
  This series contains Farrar's drafts of writings ranging from poetry to prose. The series also includes drafts of speeches as well as lectures delivered by Farrar while teaching at New York University and Columbia University. Some poetry by Farrar is filed under "Poetry" in the Correspondence and Subject Files series.
  - "Advice to Authors' Families," holograph and typescript drafts, 1949-1950 (Box 33)
  - "Alexander Laing," typescript essay and notes, undated (Box 33)
  - Article for Touchstone, typescript rough draft, undated (Box 33)
  - Autobiographical Anthology, typescript materials and correspondence, undated (Box 33)
  - Autobiographical notes, 1950-1971 (Box 33)
  - Babcock, Frederick, JF ed. Hang up the Fiddle, typescript draft, undated (Box 33)
  - "Books in the World of Today," printed column, 1945 (Box 33)
  - Columbia article & miscellaneous typescript materials, 1955-1966 (Box 33)
  - Columbia Lectures, typescript notes, 1946-1947; 2 (Box 33)
  - Company Manners, typescript drafts, 1935; 2 (Box 33)
  - "The Condition of American Writing," typescript draft, undated (Box 34)
  - "Editorial," typescript outline and notes, undated (Box 34)
  - "An Editor's Morning," typescript draft, undated (Box 34)
  - "Footnotes to a Publishers' Sunday," typescript draft, undated (Box 34)
  - "For Author's League Bulletin," typescript draft, 1944 (Box 34)
  - Foreword to W. S. Maugham's The Making of a Saint, typescript draft and proofs, 1967 (Box 34)
  - "Freedom of Speech," typescript draft, 1946 (Box 34)
  - "The Galloping Age," typescript draft, 1947 (Box 34)
  - "Guy McCrone," holograph draft, undated (Box 34)
  - "He's in the Cavalry," typescript draft, undated (Box 34)
  - "If You Love Liberty," printed article, typescript and holograph drafts, undated (Box 34)
  - "Introduction to 'Worleys,'" holograph draft, undated (Box 34)
  - "John Brown's Body, " material for article for The Saturday Review, undated (Box 34)
  - "Mary Roberts Rinehart," typescript, undated (Box 34)
  - My Brother's a Hero, correspondence, 1942; 2 (Box 34)
  - Notes, typescript and holograph, undated; 3 (Box 34)
  - "Now About the Credit Union..." typescript, undated (Box 34)
  - "Mr. Farrar's Play Ideas," typescript, undated (Box 34)
  - Poems, typescript and holograph, 1949-1969; 2 (Box 34)
  - Private Relations, typescript drafts, undated; 4 (Box 35)
  - "A Publisher Goes to the Movies," typescript, undated (Box 35)
  - "Radio Talk: 1," typescript, undated (Box 35)
  - Review of American Memoir by Henry Seidel Canby, 1947 (Box 35)
  - Review of Man and Shadow by Alfred Kreymborg, undated (Box 35)
  - "A Selective Bibliography for Students in the Course 'The Practice of Book Publishing,'" typescript copy, undated (Box 35)
  - Speeches and Talks
    - Chicago, February 1949 (Box 35)
    - Chicago, 1951 (Box 35)
    - "Literature Between Two Wars", 1948 (Box 35)